iihs.org 2019-12-14

# Copyright information and privacy policy

All content (such as images and text) available on the Insurance Institute for Highway Safety/Highway Loss Data Institute internet site is copyrighted property of the Institutes, unless indicated otherwise. The content on this website is made available for limited noncommercial, educational and personal use only; a user may download content to share with others for limited noncommercial and educational purposes without requesting specific permission. When using content for limited noncommercial, educational and personal use, the source of the content should be cited as www.iihs.org.

Repetitive1 noncommercial, educational, or personal use and copying or redistribution in any manner for commercial use is not permitted without written permission from the Institute. Requests to use our content for repetitive noncommercial, educational, or personal use and for commercial use can be made by emailing our Legal Department at [legal@iihs.org](mailto:legal@iihs.org). Requests should include the following information:

Requests for website usage will be subject to the following guidelines:

  * a description of the Institutes’ content for which the requester seeks permission to use;
  * a description of the requester’s project and how the Institutes’ content will be used to support the project;
  * a description of the make-up and size of the intended audience;
  * a description of how the project will be distributed (e.g. web, print) and for how long; and
  * whether the requester will charge for access to its project.   

Please contact the Legal Department at [legal@iihs.org](mailto:legal@iihs.org) if you have any questions concerning the Institutes’ copyright policy.

## Privacy policy

Thank you for visiting the website of the Insurance Institute for Highway Safety and the Highway Loss Data Institute (collectively, the Institute). This Privacy Policy explains the Institute's online information practices.

The Institute uses [Google Analytics](http://www.google.com/analytics/) for tracking web statistics. Google Analytics runs code in your browser that sends the following information to the Institute:

  * Internet Protocol (IP) address from which you accessed the Institute's website (Every computer connected to the Internet is assigned a unique number, or IP address, usually in country-based blocks);
  * Type of browser and operating system used to access the Institute's website;
  * Date and time you accessed the Institute's website;
  * Institute pages that you visited; and
  * If you linked to the Institute's website from another website, the address of that other website.

Google Analytics also collects other detailed information, which it explains in its own [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/). Google will ask for your consent before using any personal information that it acquires for a purpose other than those that are set out in its Privacy Policy. The Institute neither controls nor is responsible for whether any third-party service provider, including Google and Google's subsidiaries, embeds content or tracks your information. Additionally, the Institute neither controls nor is responsible for the manner in which the third-party service provider uses your information.

The Institute uses the information that it collects to count the number of visitors visiting its website and the various web pages therein, and also to provide the Institute with certain guidance on where to make its website more useful and user-friendly. This type of information is retained indefinitely.

If you contact the Institute via email, the Institute will use your personal information (such as your name, email address, telephone number, and/or postal address) to respond to your request. The Institute does not provide your personal information to other organizations.

The Institute sells its consumer videos through an outside vendor, [2Checkout.com](https://www.2checkout.com/). 2Checkout guarantees secure sales. Please see 2Checkout.com's own [Privacy Policy](https://www.2checkout.com/legal/privacy/) for more information.

The Institute's website includes links to websites maintained by other organizations. When you link to another website, you are no longer on the Institute's website or subject to the Institute's Privacy Policy. Instead, you will be subject to the privacy policy of the new website that you are visiting. The Institute does not endorse any information or services that these external sites offer and only provides the links as a service to you.

For information on how to disable cookies in your specific browser, navigate [here](https://www.internetcookies.org/disable-cookies/).

* * *
